Guide to the Collection of Bookplates by Wim Zwiers
Yale University Arts Library
Collection of Bookplates by Wim Zwiers
1945-1960
BKP 5
Yale University Arts Library
1.67
(4 boxes)
This collection contains bookplates by the Dutch artist Wim Zwiers. Many are signed proofs or numbered prints.
Zwiers, Wim, 1922-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Yale Bookplate Collection was formerly housed in Sterling Memorial Library. The collection was incorporated into the Arts of the Book Collection in 1984 and then moved to the Seeley G. Mudd Library in 1990. In 2011 it was transferred to the Robert B. Haas Family Arts Library.
Associated Materials
See also the Andrews Memorial Bookplate Collection of Irene D. Andrews Pace (Personal Bookplates) (Call # BKP 2).
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Wim Zwiers was born in Rotterdam in 1922. He worked as a graphic artist, primarily as a wood and copper engraver, but also as a draftsman and painter. He executed hundreds of ex libris designs.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains bookplates by the Dutch artist Wim Zwiers. Many are signed proofs or numbered prints. Of particular note are drawings and proofs for a bookplate Zwiers designed for Irene D. Andrews Pace. In addition to bookplates, the collection contains several New Year's greeting cards also designed by Zwiers.
Arrangement
Arranged in alphabetical order by bookplate patron.
Bookplates; Zwiers, Wim, 1922-; Andrews, Irene Dwen, 1892-
- Bookplates
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains bookplates as well as a few greeting cards.
  - Asperslag – Asselberg, 1955-1957 undated; 3 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Baggerman – Beels, undated; 3 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bunnik, 1949-1956; 3 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Eigner – Emmens, 1947-1948; 3 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Eschauzier, 1949-1950 undated; 6 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Fleissig – Gartner, 1947-1959; 2 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Grégr – Kaspara, 1945-1952 undated; 8 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Klerks – Koster, 1946 undated; 3 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Lerperger – Mantero, 1947 undated; 3 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Mantero – Midlo, 1946-1959 undated; 5 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Muur, 1949-1952 undated; 4 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Pace, 1951; 4 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Pace, 1952-1956 undated; 5 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Premstaller – Roozen, 1950-1956 undated; 4 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - S – Schmidt, 1945 undated; 3 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Schwencke – Segers, 1952-1960; 4 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Shaftel, 1950-1955 undated; 4 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Shaftel, undated; 1 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Spindelberger – Straaten, 1951-1960; 4 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Svengsbir – Vercammen, 1954-1957 undated; 5 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    General note
    Also mounted with the Svengsbir bookplate is the bookplate of J. Cerny.
  - W – Wees, 1949 undated; 4 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Werner – Winkler, 1954 undated; 2 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Zwiers, 1947-1954 undated; 4 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Zwiers, undated; 4 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Zwiers, 1945-1955; 4 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Zwiers, 1949; 1 (Box 4, Folder 26)